Dhruv Sharma

dhruv-sharma.com dhruvsharma0503@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dhruvsharma78 github.com/dhruvsharma78

ABOUT

I'm a Computer Science student at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). I specialize in full stack web development, image processing and text recognition and detection. I'm also interested in data science and analytics, with an emphasis on its use in the finance industry.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, LOS ANGELES - UCLA

Henry Samueli School of Engineering and Applied Science Computer Science

2018 - 2022 | Los Angeles, CA Major GPA: 4.0 • Cum. GPA: 3.7

Completed Courses:

- Intro to CS
- Computer Architecture
- Software Construction

Current Courses:

- Logic System Design
- Operating Systems
- Machine Learning (Stanford University, Online)

GEMS MODERN ACADEMY

High School

2014 - 2018 | Dubai, UAE

ISC: 94% • ICSE: 96%

Honors:

- KS Varkey Scholarship 2016 2018
- World Topper in Computer Science ICSE (2016) & ISC (2018)

PROJECTS & ACTIVITIES

- Developed a library that provides tools to create a completely customizable dashboard display for vehicles. Currently in use by UCLA Formula Racing.
- Currently developing a stock market analysis tool that identifies historical and live patterns along with calculating multiple technical indicators to make predictions.
- Developing a website to allow users to view detailed stock information and news. My future plans for this website are to use my aforementioned stock analysis tools to publish insights and predictions that users can use.
- Member of UCLA Bruin Racing, UCLA ACM, UCLA Algorithmic Trading, and Bruin Trading.

EXPERIENCE

UCLA IT SERVICES | BRUIN ONLINE

IT CONSULTANT

September 2019 - Present | Los Angeles, CA

• Provide primary support for clients at Bruin Online (BOL)

BLUE DOME TECHNOLOGIES

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN 2018 – 2022 | San Francisco, CA

- Researched image processing techniques to improve detection and recognition of text in images.
- Developed a custom program to split ML datasets into testing and training data.
- Researched and implemented a service to stream video files to a server and process the video while simultaneously downloading it.

BRUIN RACING

FSAE ELECTRONICS & DATA ACQUISITION TEAM 2018 - Present | Los Angeles, CA

 Assisting in the design and implementation of electrical systems of the vehicle. Designed the dashboard on the car and currently developing a custom data logging system.

ESRI

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN August 2016 & July 2017 | UAE

- Created drivers to support to add support for new file types in ArcGIS.
- Used GDAL to create an automated testing script to test support for different image file types and log the results.
- Worked on enhancing the performance of the script and significantly reducing runtime.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES C • C++ • Python • Java • JavaScript HTMI • CSS

FRAMEWORKS NodeJS • React • Express • Sass

POPULAR LIBRARIES Pandas • Matplotlib • Numpy Tesseract • OpenCV

DESIGN Adobe XD • Adobe Photoshop • Adobe Illustrator • Final Cut Pro

OTHERS Microsoft Excel (Microsoft Certified Specialist)